<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications | Dijun Liu</title><link>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/</link><atom:link href="https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Publications</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 04:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Publications</title><link>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/</link></image><item><title>Working Paper</title><link>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/journal-article/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 04:43:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/journal-article/</guid><description>&lt;p>Abs: In this chapter, I study the variation of the book-to-market (B/M) ratio across firms and over time. The B/M ratio, a firm characteristic defined as the book value over the market value of equity, plays an important role in finance theory and practice. In this chapter, I first replicate and extend the Chapter of “Value Premium” in Bali, Engle, and Murray (2016). Second, recent work debates on whether the B/M ratio should also account for intangible capital. I estimate three versions of internally generated intangible capital, use it to adjust B/M ratio and confirm that including intangible capital does improve the performance of value strategy. One of the contributions of this paper is to compare methods to estimate intangibles. The long-short value premium and the cumulative return of HML factor favor bm&lt;sup>Eisfeldt&lt;/sup> compared with bm&lt;sup>Peters&lt;/sup> and bm&lt;sup>Ewens&lt;/sup>. Nevertheless, none of them can expand the mean-variance frontier spanned by four other factors, and they all experience persistent drawdowns in recent decades. Third, to delve into the time-series and cross-sectional behavior of B/M ratio and its associated value premium, I conduct two sub-sample analyses: pre- or post-1999 analysis and high tech sector or not analysis. The pre- or post-1999 analysis indicates that the positive relation between all the four versions of B/M and future stock returns is much weaker post-1999. High tech sector or not analysis does not corroborate the argument that the death of value strategy is caused by the conservative accounting biases in book value. The selection of a better estimation method for intangibles is hampered as it changes across contexts. Last, I show that instead of using intangible capital to adjust book value, leveraging the ratio of intangible capital over market value can deliver HML factors which feature much higher cumulative returns and smaller drawdowns in recent decades. The drawdowns of HML factors are closely associated with the change of relative valuation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working Paper</title><link>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/preprint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 04:37:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/preprint/</guid><description>&lt;p>Equity duration is the present value weighted cash flow maturity. It measures the sensitivity of the price to the change of interest rate. Using a present value decomposition approach, I calculate the contribution of cash flow news and discount rate news to the unexpected returns for portfolios based on equity duration. Surprisingly, the cash flow news is the main driver across portfolios that are composed of stocks with long duration or short duration. Stocks characterized by a shorter duration earn return premium over stocks with a longer duration. Though the short duration premium embeds value premium, it cannot be a substitute for the intangible adjusted book-to-market ratio. Portfolio analyses indicate that the premium is concentrated on small stocks and stocks that are possibly short-sale constrained.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Job Market Paper</title><link>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/conference-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dijunliu1995.github.io/publication/conference-paper/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>